Yuma, let's go home—
（礼奈(れいな)）佑真(ゆうま)　今日も一緒に帰ろ…
Too slow! Keep pace with
the goldfish as it turns!
（桐仁(きりひと)）遅い！
金魚の急な方向転換についていけ！
えっ？　なに？　これ
What the heck's going on?
Two... One...
（桐仁）２ １…
（小関(おぜき)･蛍(けい)）ンッ… ンッ…
Okay, stop.
（桐仁）はい やめ
（小関たち）ハァハァ…
Hold some water in your mouth.
（桐仁）水を口に含んで…
Spirit!
はっきよい！
（ぶつかり合う音）
What's with all these weird training drills?
みんな
なに変なこと やらされてんの？
…つうか
Though, frankly...
（佑真）シュッ…　シュッ…
（礼奈）佑真のが いちばん変
Yuma's the one doing the strangest drill.
（佑真）シュッ…　シュッ…
（佑真）
シュッ…　シュッ…
Bout 5
“The Refreshing Sumo Wrestler, Sada Mizuki”
What are you doing?
Slapping a ping pong ball?
（礼奈）なに？　それ
ピンポン球に突っ張り？
Yeah. I keep my back straight
and use my legs and loins to strike.
（佑真）おう　上体は起こしたまま
足腰を使って 強く打つ
It'll prevent my opponents from
pulling me to the ground, apparently.
これが
引き技に落ちない突きの練習らしい
"Apparently"?
“らしい”って…
ホントに それで強くなんの？
Are you really gonna get
any stronger doing that?
And anyway, why are you listening to him?
…つうか
よく あいつのやり方に従えるわね
He makes you do these crazy exercises
while he just sits on his ass the whole time.
人にはムチャクチャなことを
強いておいて—
自分は
偉そうに ふんぞり返ってるヤツの
（佑真）まあ ハタから見りゃ
そう見えるんだろうな
Yeah, it probably looks that way
from the outside looking in.
Frankly, I don't like the guy, either.
ぶっちゃけ 俺も
あいつのことは気に食わねえよ
And the reason for that is...
何が気に食わねえって
あの野郎—
That jerk puts his neck on the line
when we've got our backs turned.
人には見えねえ所で体張ってやがる
But what he chooses to do on
his own time is his own business.
（佑真）ただ あいつが裏で
どんなに頑張ろうが それは別の話
I won't do what anyone else
says unless I agree with it.
納得がいかねえことには従えねえ
それでも…
Still...
I need precise footwork to
pull off advanced techniques.
（千比路(ちひろ)）俺の多彩な技を
生かすには 正確な足さばき
The goldfish bowl resembles a sumo ring.
金魚鉢を土俵に見立てて—
I'm fighting in a sumo ring,
not a wrestling ring!
マットのリングじゃない
土俵の大きさ…
I'm gonna force my body to remember!
感覚を体に覚え込ませるんだ！
Keeping water in my mouth trains me
（小関）
水を含んで 息を止めながら—
to finish a match quickly
while holding my breath.
一気に勝負を決める稽古ってことか
I get it. That's totally logical.
なるほど
理にかなっている気がする
（佑真）
みんな うすうす思っていたことだ
Everyone's thinking the same
in the back of their mind.
Half of us have never done sumo before.
俺たちは 半分が相撲の素人
If we trained the way everyone else does,
よそと同じことをやってたら
日本一になんてなれやしねえ
we'd have zero chance of
becoming the best in Japan.
That's why we're doing this.
だからだろうな
ヤツの奇抜なやり方は—
His bizarre training techniques
are designed to help us shake off
our anxiety and impatience.
逆に
俺らの不安や焦りを振り払うんだ
He never fully explains things,
あいつの説明は 相変わらず
足りねえが それは もういいさ
but I don't mind that now.
The sensation's all I need.
手応えで伝わる
My body...
体が… 本能が言ってんだよ
My instincts are telling me one thing...
If I follow him, I'll become stronger!
“あいつに ついていけば
強くなれる”ってな
Does he feel the same way?
あいつも そうなの？
（火ノ丸(ひのまる)）ンンッ…
No! Your movements are too erratic!
（桐仁）ダメだ！
全然 動きがバラバラだぞ！
Even your captain's beating him.
（礼奈）部長にまで負けてんじゃん
This is meant to make
him less anxious, isn't it?
あれで 不安はないって言えるの？
Just look at the expression on his face.
…んなもん
ツラ見りゃ分かんだろう
One more time!
（火ノ丸）もう１本！
I read something a long time ago.
（佑真）昔 何かで見たんだけどよ
It said that the best instructors are the
ones who instill belief in their athletes.
優秀な指揮官の条件は 選手に
できると思い込ませることだそうだ
If that's true,
だとしたら
あいつは なかなか有能だぜ
he's a first-class instructor.
Okay, everyone, gather around.
（桐仁）
よし　みんな　集まってくれ
As you probably know, there's
very little time until the tournament.
分かっていると思うが
大会まで時間がない
So on our next day off,
なので 今度の休日は—
we're going to go train at Ishigami
High School in the next town over.
隣町の石神(いしがみ)高校に
出稽古に行くことにした
Ishigami High School...
（小関）石神高校…
It's time to show the fruits of my labor!
（千比路）特訓の成果を
見せる時が来たようだな！
I feel like I can beat a first-year now.
（蛍）今だったら
同じ１年生なら倒せる気がします
Ishigami High School came second
in last year's Kanto tournament.
（桐仁）
石神高校は 昨年の関東大会で—
準優勝している強豪校だ
１年生のレベルも高い
Their first-years will be strong, too.
And...
それに…
The middle school yokozuna
and national treasure,
あそこには 中学生横綱の国宝
三日月宗近(みかづきむねちか)もいる
Mikazuki Munechika, is on their team.
The middle school yokozuna?
（佑真･蛍）中学横綱？
Oh, so that's where he ended up, huh?
あいつが おるのか
Sounds like a good opportunity to try out
my new and improved Hundred Demon Takedown.
百鬼薙(ひゃっきな)ぎを改良した新技を試すには
ちょうどいいかもしれんのぅ
No, you'll be going somewhere else.
（桐仁）いや
お前には違う所に行ってもらう
You must fight a range of strong opponents
in order to perfect your new technique.
（桐仁）新技を完成させるには
とにかく たくさん—
高いレベルの相手と
対人戦をこなさないといけない
So...
つうわけで…
Head to this address.
ここの住所に行ってくれ
More like Primate
Asshole
Ishigami Private
High School
Idiot
It's sea,
you idiot
↓
See of
blood
A
k
e
m
i
Congrats
（蛍）えっ？　ここが石神高校？
This is Ishigami High School?
Ishigami High School is said to be the most
dangerous high school in the prefecture.
（小関）石神高校といえば—
県内でも
ダントツに治安の悪い学校だからね
Jeez. Why did we have to come to
a place like this on a school holiday?
（礼奈）もう…
なんで せっかくの休みなのに—
こんなとこに
来なきゃいけないのよ？
No one forced you to come.
別に 来いだなんて言ってねえぞ
（蛍）あの…　國崎(くにさき)さんは
なんで来てないんですか？
Um, why isn't Kunisaki-san with us?
He failed his midterms,
so he had to take a remedial class.
（桐仁）あの人は
中間テストで赤点取って—
学校で補習受けてますよ
That's a pity. He was
looking forward to coming.
（小関）
あんなに楽しみにしてたのにね
Who the hell're you?!
Tryna move in on our patch?!
（不良）
何だ？　てめえら　殴り込みか！
ヒャッハ〜！　…ろすぞ おら！
We're gonna take ya down!
（２人）ヒイ〜ッ！
（礼奈）フン…
ヒュ〜！
マブイ女がいるじゃねえか
Oh, man, talk about a smokin' hot babe!
Why don't ya ditch these losers and come
hang with someone awesome inste—
そんなシャバ僧と
つるんでないで…
Back off!
（佑真）てめえ…
（不良）一緒に遊ぼうぜ…
…タアッ！
Senpai, please leave them alone.
（沙田(さだ)）
先輩　やめてあげてくださいよ
You're scaring her.
彼女 怖がってるじゃないですか
S-Sada! I was... actin' in self-defense
'cause these thugs were threatenin' us.
（不良）さ… 沙田！
俺は 殴り込みに来た こいつらを…
Actually, we're here to see the sumo club.
（桐仁）あの…　僕らは
相撲部に用があって来たんですが…
The sumo club?!
相撲部！？
Oh, so you're guests of the sumo club?
な… なんだ
相撲部のお客さんでしたか
Hey, guys, make way for 'em!
おう お前ら　行くぞ
You guys are a sumo club? That's great!
（沙田）君たち 相撲部なの？
いいな かわいい女子マネがいて
You've even got yourself a cute manager.
I-I'm not actually their manager.
べ… 別に
私は そんなんじゃないし
（女子学生１）あっ 沙田君！
（２人）うん？
It's Sada-kun!
You're right! He's so hot!
（女子学生２）
ホントだ！　キャ〜 カッコイイ！
Sorry I can't guide you guys.
（沙田）
皆さん　案内できなくて ごめんね
The dojo's over that way.
道場は あっちにあるから　じゃ！
Bye!
この学校にも
あんなタイプの人がいるんですね
This school has guys like that, too, huh?
What is that?
（蛍）何ですか？　あれ
でっかいタイヤ…
A huge tire?
Tire flips. Very nice.
（桐仁）タイヤフリップか　いいね
One that size probably weighs about 150 kg.
あの大きさは150キロってとこかな
Simply picking it up and flipping it
gives your whole body a workout.
持ち上げて ひっくり返すだけでも
かなりの全身運動になる
（蛍）えっ？　150キロ？
150 kg?!
You can also hit tires with hammers
or just push them along the ground.
（桐仁）ほかにも
ハンマーで たたいたり—
地面に寝かせて押したり
いろいろと使えるんだ
How intense...
（小関）すごい熱気
Just so you know, the guys
training out here are all first-years.
（桐仁）
ちなみに 外で筋トレしている あれ
全部１年生だね
（蛍）えっ！　あの体格で？
With those physiques?!
（小関）ビ… ビビるな 俺
D-Don't be intimidated!
Hey! Who're you?
（金盛(かなもり)）おい　何だ？　お前ら
（小関）ヒイッ！
Only club members are allowed out here.
（金盛）部外者が
こんな所に来るんじゃねえ
Excuse me. You're Kanamori-san,
the club captain, correct?
あの…　主将の金盛さんですよね？
突然 すみません
We apologize for barging in like this.
Ishigami
High
School
Sumo
Club
Practice with us?!
（金盛）出稽古だ？
You waltz in here and
say something like that?
突然やって来て 何言ってやがる
礼節というものを知らんのか！
Didn't anyone teach you guys manners?
You didn't tell them we were coming?!
（小関）
お前 アポなしで来たのかよ！
（金盛）
…んで お前ら どこの学校だ？
Anyway, what school are you from?
Odachi High School.
大太刀(おおだち)高校です
Dachi High?
（間宮(まみや)）
ダチ高？　栄華大(えいがだい)の久世(くぜ)を—
I heard Onimaru's at your school, and
he got Eiga High's Kuze back in the ring!
本気にさせた鬼丸(おにまる)がいるって
ウワサの？
What? Which one's Onimaru?
なに？　どいつだ？
Oh, he had some things to
take care of, so he's not with us.
（桐仁）
あっ 今日は所用で 彼は来てません
（２人）うん？　ハァ…
Then, what's the point
of practicing with you?
（金盛）それじゃ お前らなんかと
稽古したって意味ねえな
ほほう…　鬼丸以外は
警戒する必要はなしですか？
So you think Onimaru's the only one
on our team worth keeping an eye on?
なあ　これ以上は もうムリだよ
帰ろうぜ
Hey, we should quit while we're ahead.
Let's head back.
Don't worry. Let me handle this.
（桐仁）大丈夫だって　俺に任せて
Guys like this are easy to provoke.
こういうタイプは
挑発に乗りやすいから
That guy charged at a tire that weighs
as much as a heavyweight and stopped it.
（金盛）こいつ…
重量級の力士ほどの
重さがある このタイヤを—
ぶちかましで止めやがった
For some reason, my body didn't falter.
（小関）
なんか 全然 体がブレなかったな
Has the seaweed harvesting
made my trunk stronger?
ワカメ漁の効果か
体幹が強くなってる？
（金盛）こら！
Hey! Don't be so careless, first-years!
いいかげんなことしてんじゃねえぞ
１年！
（部員たち）
ヒイッ！　すみません！
We're sorry!
Apologize to him, not me.
謝る相手が違うだろうが
えっ？　あっ いや　俺は別に…
Oh, no, that's not necessary.
We're very sorry!
（部員たち）すんませんした！
（小関）えっ？
What do you think of our captain?
どうです？　ウチの部長は
See how Onimaru isn't the only
interesting member of our club?
これで ウチが
鬼丸だけじゃないっていうのが—
分かってもらえましたかね？
Why not let them join in?
（真田(さなだ)）まあ いいじゃないか
わざわざ ここまで来てくれたんだ
They came all the way out here.
フン…　別に
お前の口車に乗るわけじゃねえ
I'm not getting taken in
by your smooth talk.
But we do need to make up
for what happened.
…が 今は わびもしなきゃならねえ
Come in. You can practice with us.
入れ　合同稽古をしてやる
So this is where he is.
（荒木(あらき)）ここにヤツがいるんだな？
Odachi High School
フン…
待ってろよ 鬼丸
Just you wait, Onimaru.
（千比路）あ〜 くそ！
Dammit! I wanted to
fight someone strong!
俺も 強いヤツと
戦いたかった！
But what can you do?
でも まあ しゃあねえ
道場で 金魚と戯れっか
Guess I'll go to the dojo
and play with the goldfish.
（西郷）あっ 國崎
（千比路）どうした？　何か用か？
Kunisaki!
What's up? You need something?
No, there's a student from
another school in your club room.
（舟木）いや　相撲部に
他校の生徒が入り込んでんだよ
What?
（千比路）なに？
His aura tells me
he's no ordinary guy.
この気配 ただ者じゃねえな
Who the hell are you?
何者だ？　てめえ
（爪とぎの音）
おい…
Hey...
（殴る音）
（千比路）起きろ この野郎！
Wake up, idiot!
You just made me look stupid
for trying to talk to you!
話しかけた俺が
バカみたいじゃねえか！
H-He hit someone he doesn't know in the head!
（３人）し… 知らんヤツの頭を…
Ishigami
Oh, I fell asleep.
（荒木）あ〜 寝てたか
悪い悪い
Ishigami
Sorry about that.
I got tired of waiting.
ちょっと
待つのに疲れてね
Ishi High?
（千比路）石高？
（荒木）あのさ…
Say...
Could you go fetch the sumo
by the name of Onimaru?
（荒木）鬼丸って人
ちょっと連れてきてくれない？
Huh?
（千比路）ああ？
（荒木）強いらしいね 彼
I've heard he's good.
I'm Araki Gennosuke.
俺 荒木源之助(げんのすけ)っていいまして
You could say I'm here to
scout your sumo club.
まあ 相撲部の偵察ってやつですな
Scout?
（千比路）偵察だ？
You're like a moth to
a light... er, a flame?
てめえみたいなのをな
飛んで火に入る春の…
いや 夏の？　ハッ…
I am Onimaru!
（千比路）わしが鬼丸じゃ！
（西郷たち）はぁ！？
Oh, you're the guy?
おお！　あんたが？
Luck's on my side for a change.
俺にしては珍しくツイてる
こんなに すんなり会えるとは
I can't believe I found you so quickly.
No, wait.
（荒木）いや 違う　ツイてねえな
（千比路）うん？
I can't call myself lucky.
My dream is to become the
strongest mixed martial artist.
（荒木）俺の夢はさ 総合格闘技で
頂点を取ることなんだけどね
Ishigami Private
High School
I heard Ishi High had
the strongest sumo club,
（荒木）石高で いちばん強いのは
相撲部って聞いて—
俺は 迷わず入部を決めたよ
so I jumped at the chance to enroll there.
But then, I heard someone named Onimaru
そしたら あの栄華大で
草薙(くさなぎ)っていう国宝相手に—
took on Eiga High's
national treasure, Kusanagi,
大暴れした鬼丸ってヤツが
近所にいるっていうじゃねえか
and he was right in my neck of the woods.
へえ…　この間のことが
そんなにウワサになってんのか
Are people really talking about that?
I was hoping to spar with you,
but I guess I wasted my time.
（荒木）あわよくば
手合わせ願おうと来てみたけど—
（荒木）外れだな
（千比路）なっ…
You don't seem strong enough.
あんたが それほどの強者(つわもの)には
とても見えない
I'm not calling you weak.
別に
あんたが弱いとは言ってねえよ
But if you really did give
Kusanagi a run for his money,
ただ 草薙相手に
いい勝負ができたってんなら—
you must've got pretty lucky.
よほどツイてたんだね
Well, they do say luck is a skill, too.
まあ 運も まぐれも
実力のうちっていうしね
I'll have to wait for nationals to
roll around to fight someone strong.
強者(つわもの)との対戦は 全国行ったときの
お楽しみってことか
Sorry for intruding.
ジャマしたね
（千比路）
ハハハハッ…　教えてやるよ
Let me show you
that your eyes are empty holes,
and you are indeed a lucky boy!
お前の その目は節穴で—
しかも なかなかの
ラッキーボーイだってことをよ
へえ…
Well, then. Shall we begin sparring?
では そろそろ
ぶつかり稽古を始めましょうか
Okay.
いいだろう
Gojo-san will fight first.
じゃ 最初は五條(ごじょう)さんから
Yeah.
おう
Then, Mamiya will start for us.
じゃ こっちからは間宮
お前が行け
Get in there.
（間宮）ウッス
Okay!
Mamiya Keiichi, a second-year...
A heavyweight: 182 cm tall,
and weighing 166 kg.
身長182センチ
体重166キロのヘビー級だ
How effective will Gojo-san's
karate-infused slaps be?
五條さんの空手仕込みの張り手が
どこまで通用するか…
This guy's huge.
（佑真）でけえ
間近で見ると すげえ圧力だぜ
Seeing him up close just
makes him more intimidating.
Spirit!
（審判）はっきよい！
させねえ！
（突く音）
No way!
むっ…　こいつ…
あっ…　俺の張り手が通用する！
My slap worked!
Gojo-san, can I have a minute?
（桐仁）
五條さん　ちょっといいですか？
Please avoid grabbing your
opponent's mawashi belt.
五條さんは
廻(まわ)しを取りに行かないでください
Whaddaya mean?
（佑真）なんでだよ？　それじゃ
相撲が取れねえじゃねえか
How can I sumo wrestle without doing that?
What's the point of a total beginner
trying to sumo wrestle like the rest?
（桐仁）相撲の素人が まともに
相撲して どうするんですか
You need to play to your strengths.
あんたの得意なフィールドで
戦えばいいでしょう？
My strengths?
得意？
Listen closely. I want you to
fight to your heart's content.
（桐仁）いいですか？
思う存分 ケンカしてきてください
It's working.
（佑真）いけるぞ
Thanks to my training,
特訓のおかげで
相手の動きに合わせて—
I can match my opponent's
movements with my strikes.
ピンポイントで当てることが
できる！
I can hit him!
ほう…　雑だが—
He's rough around the edges, but
the fire in his strikes is impressive.
なかなか思い切りのいい突きを
打つじゃねえか
Yeah, his strikes are way too good
for him to be a beginner.
ああ
初心者とは思えない突き押し相撲だ
But...
だが…
I was going easy on you because
I thought you were a beginner.
（間宮）
初心者と思って ナメていたが…
グッ…　しまった！
Dammit!
Once Mamiya grabs someone,
he unleashes his special moves.
ああなってしまったら もう
間宮のフィールドだ
うらぁ！
（礼奈）あっ 佑真！
Yuma!
Damn!
くそ！
He'll need more work
before that tactic is effective.
さすがに
今のままでは通用しないか
Club captain, Kanamori,
vice captain, Sanada,
部長の金盛 副部長の真田
そして 今の間宮
and this Mamiya guy...
All three of them are sure to be
on their team for the tournament.
この３人は 確実に団体戦の
５人のうちのメンバーだろう
And...
それに 石高には あいつがいる
Ishi High has that other fighter, too.
But who will be their fifth member?
あと残る１人は 誰だ？
（荒木）ハアッ…
（千比路）あっ…
A one-armed shoulder throw!
これは 一本背負い！？
J-Judo?!
（３人）じゅ… 柔道！
If that's how you want to play it...
（千比路）
そっちが そう来るなら…
なに！
What?
Strongest!
（千比路）最強！
（荒木）足取り？
A leg grab?
Wh-Whoa...
（３人）す… すげえ
Hang on a sec.
（荒木）ちょっと待った
（千比路）うん？
You're not Onimaru, are you?
お前　鬼丸じゃなくね？
（千比路）
えっ？　あ〜 うん　バレた？
Oh... you figured it out?
Your techniques are different,
and I heard he was really short!
（荒木）
なんか 聞いてた取り口と違(ちげ)えし
そもそも
鬼丸は背が小さいって話だぞ
You only just remembered that?
（３人）今更？
Damn, I've been tricked. What rotten luck!
（荒木）くそ！
ダマされるなんてツイてねえ
S-So who are you?!
じゃ… じゃ お前は 一体…
I'm Kunisaki Chihiro,
俺は國崎千比路
and I'm aiming to be the number one
mixed martial artist in the world!
いずれ 総合格闘技で
世界の頂点に立つ男だ
What? MMA?
なっ 総合？　俺と同じ？
Just like me!
Yeah! Don't copy me, Gengoro!
（千比路）そうだよ！
マネすんな ゲンゴロウ！
Huh? "Gengoro"?!
Using sumo to get a leg up in
mixed martial arts was my idea!
相撲から総合っていう
俺の異色の経歴をよ！
Forget that, I'm Gennosuke!
（荒木）それより 源之助だ！
（千比路）ああ？
Araki Gennosuke!
（荒木）荒木源之助！
（西郷たち）２人ともバカだった
They're both idiots.
Hey! What's going on in here?!
（教師）こら！　何してる？
お前か？
入り込んだ他校生ってのは
So you're the kid who's
trespassing on school property.
（荒木）
あっ…　おっと タイムアップか
Oh, I guess time's up.
We'll finish our bout another day.
勝負は お預けだな　残念
Shame.
But perhaps I was fortunate
to meet you, Chiharu.
いや　あんたに会えたことは
ツイてたかな　チハル
It's Chihiro!
（千比路）“チヒロ”だ！
I'll see you at the Inter High.
（荒木）
続きはインターハイだ　また会おう
Till next time.
It's one month till
the Inter High prelims.
インターハイ予選まで１か月
時間が惜しい
I need more time.
I've never regretted not
studying so much in my life!
勉強しなかったことを
こんなに後悔したのは初めてだぜ
I'm never failing a test again!
もう二度と 赤点は取らん！
Please enter the ring next, captain.
（桐仁）次は部長　お願いします
Y-Yeah.
（小関）
う… うん　頑張ってみるよ
I'll do my best.
He stopped that tire single-handedly.
（金盛）あのタイヤを
その身ひとつで止めたんだ
He's probably their strongest member.
パワーは
こいつが いちばんあるんだろう
So we'll send out...
なら ウチからは…
Oh, this looks like fun!
あれ？
なんか楽しそうなことしてる
You punk! You think a damn first-year
can show up whenever he wants?!
てめえ！　１年のくせに
なに堂々と遅刻してやがる
アアッ…　すいません
I'm sorry!
Oh, it's that guy...
（蛍）あ… あの人
（礼奈）あいつも相撲部だったの？
He's in the sumo club, too?
Can I have a turn, captain?
Let me go in the ring.
ねえ いいでしょう？　主将
次は 俺にやらせてくださいよ
You're late and asking for things?
遅刻してきたヤツが何言ってやがる
You're gonna be doing groin
stretches for the next hour!
お前は罰として
股割り ぶっ続け１時間だ！
But you know I have trouble with those!
俺が股関節 固いの知ってて
そんなこと言います？
Let him go, Kanamori.
（真田）まあ いいじゃないか 金盛
It's rare that he feels
like doing anything.
こいつが こんなに
やる気になるのも珍しいんだから
（金盛）チッ…　まったく…
甘やかすと調子に乗るぞ
Jeez, he'll never learn
if you keep going easy on him.
You're so kind, Sanada-san.
（沙田）真田さん　優しい！
（佑真）お前の相手は あいつか
Looks like he's your opponent.
You've got this one in the bag.
あれなら
お前でも倒せるんじゃないか？
That's Sada Mizuki. Or rather,
national treasure, Mikazuki Munechika.
（桐仁）あいつは 沙田美月(みづき)
国宝 三日月宗近だ
But he looks so easy-going!
（蛍）あのチャラそうなのが？
How am I supposed to
beat a national treasure?!
（小関）
そんな相手に勝てるわけないよ
In a tournament, we have to
win three bouts to beat them.
団体戦では あの連中相手に
３勝する必要があります
Even if we assume that Hinomaru
and Kunisaki will win their bouts,
（桐仁）火ノ丸と國崎さん
この２人には
確実に勝ってもらうとして…
one of you three will also
have to notch up a win.
あと この３人の中から１人—
誰かに白星を取ってもらわなきゃ
いけないんですよ
ンッ…
それは そうだけど 俺じゃ…
I know, but...
What can I do?
You're able to keep up
with Hinomaru in practice.
いつも火ノ丸と…
あいつとの稽古に
ついていけてるんだ
You must be getting better, captain.
もう以前の部長とは違うはずです
Why did Tsuji say that?
（小関）なんで辻(つじ)は
あんなこと言ったんだ…
Dammit! He's mocking me!
くそ…　ナメられてたまるか
俺だって特訓の成果を見せてやる！
I'm going to show him
how hard I've been training!
You're not getting a hold of my mawashi belt.
廻しは取らせないッスよ
He's playing with Ozeki.
（佑真）
あいつ 小関相手に遊んでやがる
You're bigger than him, so just tackle him!
（礼奈）
あんたのほうが大きいんだから—
体ごと ぶつかりなさいよ！
I hear you, but if I miss...
そんなこと言われたって
下手に攻めたら…
Hey, I know that guy.
（部員１）あいつ 知ってるぜ
We were on the same team in middle school,
but I've never seen him win a bout.
中学んときに一緒だったけど
勝ったところ 一度も見たことない
For real?
（部員２）マジかよ？
よく そんなんで続けられるな
I'm surprised he hasn't quit.
What jerks...
くそ　あいつら…
（小関）ンンッ…
（沙田）アハッ…
It's no use. I can't win this.
ダメだ　勝てない…
I don't even know how to win.
勝ち方が分からない
What am I supposed to do
against a national treasure?
国宝相手に
どうにかできるわけないじゃないか
Get your act together, captain!
しっかりしろ 部長！
あいつとの稽古を思い出せ！
Remember your training with him!
ウウッ！　ダメだぁ
It's no use!
I'm no match for you, Ushio.
やっぱり潮(うしお)には全然 かなわないや
We finally have enough members, but...
せっかく
メンバーも集まったってのに—
I'm the captain,
and I'm holding everyone back.
部長の俺が 足を引っ張ってちゃ…
（たたく音）
いってえ〜！
Ow!
ウヘヘッ…　悪い悪い
Sorry, dude.
But don't sell yourself short.
でも 自分で自分を
小さく決めつけちゃいけねえよ
You've been doing stomps for five years,
部長が
しこを踏み続けてきた５年間は…
and you've got a body anyone
would be proud of having.
その体は—
みんなに誇れる代物だってことを
ワシは知ってる
Captain, you're strong!
部長は強い
（小関）
潮が そう思ってくれてるんだ
If Ushio thinks so...
I just need to grab his mawashi belt!
廻しさえ取れれば！
（３人）あっ…
（金盛）あの体勢から耐えた！
He recovered his stance from that position?
I can do this!
いける！
（蛍たち）あっ…
（佑真）あれは…
What's that?
It's an arm hold, a technique that stops an
attack by grabbing the outside of the arm.
（桐仁）あれが“おっつけ”だ
外側から手をあてがい
攻め手を封じる技だ
And given his abilities,
it must be very powerful.
しかも ヤツの天性にかかれば
それは必殺の威力
He's got him right on the joint!
的確に関節を極(き)めてくる
With that technique, no one can grab his
mawashi belt. They can't even get near it.
これがあるかぎり
誰も廻しをつかむどころか—
触れることすら ままならない
That's why it's always
so white and pristine.
だから ヤツの廻しは
常に白く 美しいままなのさ
It was a good try.
You almost got your hands on it.
（沙田）惜しかったね
もうちょっとで届いたのに
It hurts so much, I can't breathe!
苦しい…　息ができない
Get away from him! Quick!
早く離れるんだ！
へえ…　これに耐えれるんだ？
Oh? You can withstand this?
あっ…　あの特訓の効果だ
It's thanks to our water training.
（ふんばる音）
（小関）負けたくない
I don't want to lose!
I want to get stronger, and go...
強くなって あいつと…
Go to nationals with Ushio!
潮と一緒に 全国に行くんだ！
Go, captain!
（蛍）いけ！　部長！
（佑真）そのまま押し出せ！
Push him out!
How long are you gonna mess around,
いつまで遊んでんだ　沙田！
Sada?!
You weren't bad.
あんた 悪くなかったよ
Crescent
Moon
Crescent Moon!
Crescent
Moon
ハァ…　アアッ…
What kind of move was that?
何だ？　あの技は
He threw the captain's 100 kg
body like it was nothing.
100キロはある部長を軽々と…
Hey, you guys.
（沙田）ねえ 君たち
鬼丸国綱(くにつな)　彼に伝えておいてよ
Would you mind giving Onimaru
Kunitsuna a message for me?
Tell him I'm looking
forward to facing his sumo.
君との相撲を楽しみにしてるってさ
Shibakiyama
Stable
Kirihito's being clever again.
（火ノ丸）
桐仁のヤツ 粋なことを…
Here, they produce top-ranked pros.
It's renowned for its intense practices.
ここは角界でも—
１〜２を争う
猛稽古で知られる—
Shibakiyama
Stable
The Shibakiyama Stable!
柴木山(しばきやま)部屋
That jerk Sada is late.
遅(おせ)えな 沙田の野郎
Yeah. And after we were
trying to be friendly and all...
（真田）ああ　俺らが 親睦を
深めようとしてやってんのによ
べ… べべべ… べろべろ ばあ〜
What are guys even doing?
何スか？　先輩たち
その顔 超ウケる
You look hilarious!
Sada!
（金盛たち）沙田！　てめえ！
You jerk!
（金盛たち）
べろべろ ばあ
Next Bout   "Charge!! Shibakiyama Stable"
This is too good!
やべえ！